And for the final piece of background information, I wanted to take another moment to talk about API
마지막 배경 정보로 API 비용에 대해 다시 한 번 얘기하고 싶네요
It's something that I mentioned before.
전에 말씀드린 건데요
I've also got a section on this, of course, in the readme too.
리드미에 이것에 관한 부분도 있어요
So as I said before, there is this.
아까도 말씀드렸지만 이게 있어요
It is confusing that there is typically this pro plan associated with the chat web interfaces like ChatGPT,
챗 웹 인터페이스와 관련된 프로 계획이라는 게 혼란스럽습니다 챗GPT 같은
which is typically $20 a month, uh, in the US, and similar amounts in other territories, uh, and
거요 미국에서는 월 20달러죠 다른 지역도 금액이 비슷하고요 월간
with a monthly subscription, uh, it's somewhat rate limited, but but basically there's no charge
구독을 하면 요금은 제한적이지만 한 통당 요금은 없어요
And it's, it feels like you have an almost unlimited ability to be calling the model through the chat
채팅 인터페이스를 통해 모델을 호출할 수 있는 거의 무한한 기능이 있는
interface.
것 같아요
The APIs are different.
API는 달라요
The APIs do not have a monthly subscription, but you pay per call, and the costs that you pay depends
API는 월간 구독을 하지 않지만 호출당 지불을 하고 지불하는 비용은 사용하는 모델에
on the model that you're using, and also on the number of input tokens and the number of output tokens.
따라 다르고 입력 토큰의 개수와 출력 토큰의 개수에 따라 달라지죠
And it charges you.
요금을 청구하죠
The total cost is a combination of those two.
총비용은 그 둘을 합친 거예요
It's a smaller charge based on the number of input tokens, and a slightly higher charge based on the
입력 토큰의 개수에 따라 전하가 더 적고 출력 토큰의 개수에 따라
number of output tokens.
전하가 더 높죠
But I should stress that the total costs are overall very low when it comes to the individual calls.
하지만 개인 통화의 총비용은 전반적으로 아주 낮다는 점을 강조해야겠네요
If you're looking to build a system that will be making large numbers of calls, then the numbers add
많은 양의 호출을 하는 시스템을 구축하고자 한다면 그 숫자가 쌓일 것이고 아주
up and you have to be very sensitive and aware of it as you scale.
세심하게 스케일을 조정할수록 그것을 인식해야 하죠
But in the kinds of projects we'll be working on, the costs will be quite small, and I would like
하지만 우리가 작업할 프로젝트는 비용이 아주 적게 들죠 그게 어떤 건지
to show you exactly what that is in just a second.
잠시 후에 보여드릴게요
I do want to say that generally, as far as you're concerned, for this course, probably when it comes
일반적으로 말씀드리고 싶은 건 여러분이 염려하는 한 이 과정에선 API
to API costs, what will matter the most is that these days these platforms seem to require a minimum.
비용에 관해 가장 중요한 건 요즘 이런 플랫폼들은 최소 비용이 필요한 것 같아요
In the case of OpenAI and Claude, at the moment in the US, they require you to put on at least a $5
오픈아이와 클로드의 경우 현재 미국에서는 최소 5달러의 신용카드를
worth of credit that you then draw down on.
빌린 후 돈을 써야 해요
And in this course, we won't scratch the surface of that $5, but you do have to put in that initial
이 코스에선 그 5달러의 표면을 긁진 않겠지만 초기 금액을 입력해야 합니다
amount, but there will be plenty of opportunities for you to be using that in your own projects in
하지만 여러분의 프로젝트에서 다양한 방식으로 사용할 기회가 많을 거예요
And I think it's a great investment in terms of your education and ability to use these models to build
저는 교육과 능력 면에서 큰 투자를 하는 거라고 봅니다 이런 모델을 활용해 새로운
new projects for yourself, as well as build your education and your experience.
프로젝트를 구축하고 교육과 경험을 쌓을 수 있으니까요
Having said that, if that is something that you're not comfortable with, as I say, now that we see
하지만 만약 라마를 사용하는 것이 불편하다면 라마를
how to use a llama and you've built that as part of the last exercise, you would be able to use a llama
사용하는 법을 봤고 지난 시간에 만들었으니 오픈라이, 클로드,
instead of using either OpenAI or Claude or Gemini at any point.
제미나이 대신 라마를 사용할 수 있을 거예요
You've got some practice doing that now with the last exercise, and you can put that into action should
지난 번 연습으로 연습했으니 원하면 실행에 옮길 수 있어요. Tool karaoke Tool karaoke.
If you're not comfortable with with the API costs.
API 비용이 불편하다면 말이죠
But with that background, let me now take you to a site where I can show you a bit more insight into
이제 다른 사이트로 가서 API 비트와 컨텍스트에 대한 통찰력을
the API costs and also the context.
보여드릴게요
Windows.
창문요